// src/questions.js

const questions = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: "The act of giving birth in cattle is called ………",
    options: ["Kindling", "Kidding", "Calving", "Parturition"],  
    answer: "Calving"
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: "The gestation period of a goat is ………….",
    options: ["154-155 days", "283 days", "99 days", "31 days"],   
    answer: "154-155 days"
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: "Which one of the following is not a form of livestock management?",
    options: ["Heat period", "Intensive system", "Extensive system", "Semi-intensive system"], 
    answer: "Heat period"
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question: "Animals that are not kept for breeding purpose should be ………….",
    options: ["Isolated", "Quarantined", "Castrated", "Disbudded"],
    answer: "Castrated"
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: "The average gestation period of a cow is ………",
    options: ["114 days", "210 days", "280 days", "240 days"],
    answer: "280 days"
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question: "The situation in which parents are willing and are able to make sensible decisions regarding their family is referred to as?",
    options: ["Parenthood", "Adulthood", "Responsible parenthood", "Responsible adulthood"],
    answer: "Responsible parenthood"
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: "All but one is not an important factor in responsible parenthood.",
    options: ["Decision", "Formal education", "Budget", "Planning"],   
    answer: "Formal education"
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: "Which of these is not considered as one of the importance of responsible parenthood in  national development?",
    options: ["Responsible citizen", "A healthy nation", "Alleviation of poverty", "Increase in crime rate."],   
    answer: "Increase in crime rate."
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question: " A situation when a husband and wife can no longer stay together due to frequent arguments, division and fights is referred to as?",
    options: ["Divorce and Family breakup", "Bad Family background", "All of the above", "None of the above"], 
    answer: "Divorce and Family breakup"
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question: "Budget is one of the important factors in responsible parenthood.",
    options: ["True", "False", "Maybe", "I don't know"],
    answer: "True"
  }
];

export default questions;
